{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Practical Research 1",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "PR2-L2",
    "LastModified": "14 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Week-3"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research is based on observations and experiments of theories?",
      "answer": "EMPIRICAL",
      "choices": [
        "SYSTEMATIC",
        "CONTROLLED",
        "ANALYTICAL",
        "EMPIRICAL"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research follows orderly and sequential procedures, based on valid procedures and principles?",
      "answer": "SYSTEMATIC",
      "choices": [
        "EMPIRICAL",
        "CONTROLLED",
        "ANALYTICAL",
        "SYSTEMATIC"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research keeps all variables, except those that are tested/experimented on, constant?",
      "answer": "CONTROLLED",
      "choices": [
        "EMPIRICAL",
        "SYSTEMATIC",
        "ANALYTICAL",
        "CONTROLLED"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research refers to a search for facts, answers to questions and solutions to problems?",
      "answer": "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
      "choices": [
        "OBJECTIVE",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research shows analytical procedures in gathering the data, whether historical, descriptive, and or case study?",
      "answer": "ANALYTICAL",
      "choices": [
        "EMPIRICAL",
        "SYSTEMATIC",
        "CONTROLLED",
        "ANALYTICAL"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research is unbiased and logical?",
      "answer": "OBJECTIVE",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "OBJECTIVE"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research ensures all findings are logically based on real-life situations?",
      "answer": "OBJECTIVE",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "OBJECTIVE"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research requires its own examination and produces the data needed to complete the study?",
      "answer": "ORIGINAL WORK",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "OBJECTIVE",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "ORIGINAL WORK"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research starts with a problem and ends with a problem?",
      "answer": "CYCLICAL",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "OBJECTIVE",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to maintain all communication and not fake data?",
      "answer": "Honesty",
      "choices": [
        "Objectivity",
        "Integrity",
        "Carefulness",
        "Honesty"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to avoid biases in experimental designs, data analysis, interpretation, and expert testimony?",
      "answer": "Objectivity",
      "choices": [
        "Honesty",
        "Integrity",
        "Carefulness",
        "Objectivity"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to keep your promises and agreements?",
      "answer": "Integrity",
      "choices": [
        "Honesty",
        "Objectivity",
        "Carefulness",
        "Integrity"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to avoid careless errors and negligence?",
      "answer": "Carefulness",
      "choices": [
        "Honesty",
        "Objectivity",
        "Integrity",
        "Carefulness"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to share data, results, ideas and tools and be open to criticism and new ideas?",
      "answer": "Openness",
      "choices": [
        "Confidentiality",
        "Responsible Publication",
        "Responsible Mentoring",
        "Openness"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to protect confidential communication?",
      "answer": "Confidentiality",
      "choices": [
        "Openness",
        "Responsible Publication",
        "Responsible Mentoring",
        "Confidentiality"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means that research should have been conducted in an ethical and responsible manner?",
      "answer": "Responsible Publication",
      "choices": [
        "Openness",
        "Confidentiality",
        "Responsible Mentoring",
        "Responsible Publication"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to help educate, mentor, and advise others?",
      "answer": "Responsible Mentoring",
      "choices": [
        "Openness",
        "Confidentiality",
        "Responsible Publication",
        "Responsible Mentoring"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to treat all peers fairly?",
      "answer": "Respect Colleagues",
      "choices": [
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Legality",
        "Respect Colleagues"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to strive to promote social good and avoid social harm?",
      "answer": "Social Responsibility",
      "choices": [
        "Respect Colleagues",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Legality",
        "Social Responsibility"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to avoid discrimination against colleagues or students on the basis of sex, races, ethnicity, and or others?",
      "answer": "Non-Discrimination",
      "choices": [
        "Respect Colleagues",
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Legality",
        "Non-Discrimination"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to be informed and obey relevant laws and institutional and governmental policies?",
      "answer": "Legality",
      "choices": [
        "Respect Colleagues",
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Legality"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to give proper acknowledgment or credits to all researchers?",
      "answer": "Respect of Intellectual Property",
      "choices": [
        "Human Subject",
        "Legality",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Respect of Intellectual Property"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to minimize risks that involve human lives, dignity, and privacy?",
      "answer": "Human Subject",
      "choices": [
        "Respect of Intellectual Property",
        "Legality",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Human Subject"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    }
  ]
}
